Ogundotun Balikiz

Frontend Developer

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ogundotunbalkiss/

https://twitter.com/Balkissty

https://github.com/balkissty

PROFILE

I am a Frontend developer with expertise in developing responsive websites and proficiently implementing Figma designs. I have a keen interest in acquiring knowledge about the latest technologies, transforming concepts into actuality, and working alongside committed teams to create effective and resilient applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

02/2023 - present Abuja, Nigeria

Nigeria Police Force Central motor Registry ∅

- Meeting with development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Identifying web based user interactions.
- Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components.
- Troubleshooting and debugging application codes.
- Monitoring and improving frontend performances.
- Documenting application changes and developing updates.

Frontend Developer 09/2022 - 01/2023 Abuja, Nigeria

Hero Technologies

- Develop new user-facing features
- Collaboration with team members to ensure technical feasibility of designs
- Build reusable codes
- Working with APIs to ensure interactivity.

Frontend Developer Intern

01/2021 - 03/2022 Lagos, Nigeria

Pheeque Company

- Building, creating and maintaining responsive web pages with gratifying aesthetics including usability.
- Using common react tools such as Redux, IDEs and RESTful APIs.
- Use of CSS frameworks such as Bootstrap and Tailwind for responsive, mobile first UI development.
- Proficient understanding of web markup, including HTML5, CSS3.
- Basic understanding of server-side CSS pre-processing platforms, such as LESS and SASS.
- Proficient understanding of client-side scripting and JavaScript frameworks.
- Proficient understanding of code versioning tools.

EDUCATION

Front End Development

2019 - 2020Lagos, Nigeria

Nigerian Women Techsters - Tech4Dev Bootcamp

BAgric/Animal Science

2011 - 2016 Osogbo, Nigeria

Osun State University

SKILLS

Practical knowledge of Frontend Technologies

Html5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, REACTJS, TAILWIND AND BOOTSTRAP CSS

REST APIs

Experience with REST APIs and third-party libraries

Version control

Proficient understanding of Git and Github.

Organizational skill

Planning and ability to work with time

Collaboration

Strong team spirit

Learning Ability

Quick and sound learning ability

Adaptability

Adaptability to environmental condition and technological advancement

LANGUAGES

Html	• • • •	Css	• • • • •
Javascript	• • • •	Reactjs	• • • • •
Bootstrap	• • • •	Tailwindcss	• • • •

PROJECTS

E-commerce website *⊘*

Central Motor registry

https://cmris.npf.gov.ng/

Striit App 🔗

Striit is more than just an app to check for available parking spots and bylaw updates. It's a community of drivers and app users helping one another avoid parking tickets, keeping cars safe, and making parking better—together.

02/2023 - 05/2023